PERSONAL INFORMATION

First name/surname: Irene Chameyeva

Address: Komsomolskaya str. 22/33, Novocheboksarsk, Russia

Telephone (Mobile): +7 (8352) 8 917 650 40 17

E-mail: Irene.chameyeva@gmail.com

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Translating,

Interpreting English-Russian and Russian –English Translator since 1998, numerous

translation projects which include translation of all types of texts,

documents, letters, books, drawings, websites etc. in many fields including Oil and Gas Industry, Engineering Industry, Construction, Economy and

Business, Finance, Textile and etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

September 2010 – Present

Working freelance providing a translation and interpretation service to

clients where needed.

.

2005-2010

Name and address

of employer

Position

i osition

Chetra - Industrial Machineries, JSC, Cheboksary, Russia

Export sales regional manager

Duties: Conducting negotiations and communication with foreign companies,

making commercial offers, preparation of documents for participation in international tenders, preparation of banking, commercial and shipping documents, documentation for customs clearance, work with banks and

carriers.

2003-2005

Name and address Foreign Trade Company "Textilmach", Cheboksary, Russia

of employer

Position Export sales manager

Duties: Conducting negotiations and communication with foreign companies, making

commercial offers, preparation of documents for participation in international

tenders, preparation of banking, commercial and shipping documents,

documentation for customs clearance, preparation of draft contracts and executive control of sales contracts, work with banks and carriers, monthly and weekly reports

on sales, market research.

1999-2003

Name and address

ess Foreign Trade Company "Textilmach", Cheboksary, Russia

of employer

Position Senior translator

Duties: Translation of international contracts, commercial offers, business letters,

banking, commercial and shipping documents, legal, scientific and technical documentation, interpreting in negotiations, presentations and

exhibitions, during start-up and commissioning of equipment,

accompanying foreign delegations.

1998-1999

Name and address of employer

Textilmach, JSC

Position General Director Assistant

Duties: Receiving and distribution of tel. calls, arrangement of working days and

business trips of the General Director.

1992-1998

Name and address

Secondary school No 13, Novocheboksarsk

of employer

Position English teacher

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

1986 -1991 University in Cheboksary, Faculty of foreign languages (English and

German)

2005 Currency Regulation and Currency Control in the Russian Federation, training

courses in Russian Academy of State Service at the President of the RF.

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Familiar with translation software tools.
- Able to fluently speak English, German good.
- Excellent communication and social skills.
- Highly skilled in Microsoft Office, Adobe Acrobat, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, AutoCAD, InDesign, Infix, Visio
- Willing to travel and able to meet tight deadlines.